

DUSHIANT RATHORE

CONSULTANT ARCHITECT - METRO RAIL | AVIATION design documentation | site coordination

PROFILE

Highly creative Registered Architect and Management professional with 19+ years of extensive experience in Design development to well-developed execution footprints on site.

Expertise includes Design review, Technical & Commercial review and Coordination of Architectural Design Development with Documentation

SKILLS

Client relations
Team management
Architectural Design
Project Management
Site Coordination
Problem Resolution

DOMAIN EXPERTISE

Metro Rail

Healthcare Architecture Community Development Integrated Townships Group Housing Commercial & Residential

EXPERIENCE

LEAD ARCHITECT • MEINHARDT EPCM • 2022 – Present

- As Project Lead spearheading currently for Terminal Planning & Design for ADANI Jaipur Int Airport & Guwahati Int Airport wrt integration of International and Domestic operations.
- Redesigning Terminal Landside area inclusive of approach Roads with revised traffic flows, arrival & departure kerb & forecourt area.
- Identifying and providing instant solutions for existing interventions in operations.

SENIOR ARCHITECT • STUP CONSLT. PVT. LTD. • 2020 – 2022

- Metro (Ahmedabad-Gandhinagar) coordination for both NS & EW corridor. Metro Station retail shop Design coordination between Architects, MEP and Retailers.
- Interface coordination with System wide contractors to capture their requirements and transfer those in Architectural Plans.
- Coordinating vetting of drawings from Architectural Team/ Project Management Consultant/ VHTS Contractors, for submission/ review in line with Client requirements & Architectural Branding Manual.
- Prepared and coordinated Design Documentation for elevated Stations wrt (Cantilevered, Island and Portal Designs) including Structure, MEP and Multi-modal Integration & Inter-modal connectivity stations.
- Developed and coordinated drawings for various Authority submissions like AMC/AUDA, W. Railway, EC, TP Dept, Fire Dept. etc.).
- ADANI Ahmedabad Airport Develop Conceptual & Schematic Design for Landside Transport Infrastructure including Terminal Forecourt design, MLCP, At-Grade Roads, Parking Facilities & Staging.
- Pedestrian Bridge (SRFDCL) Coordinating of all Architectural Finishes of the iconic designed Bridge being the key decision maker.

PRINCIPAL ARCHITECT • YASH CONSTRUCTION • 2017 – 2020

- Prepare creative and sustainable architectural design proposals, making BOQs and BOLs planning, development planning, and construction administration.
- Presentation of proposed revamping of Railway Stations in Kutch region to Western Railway, Municipal authorities, and other stakeholders.
- Designing, site coordination and its completion of varied projects viz.
 Housing, Group Housing, Hospitals, Institutes, Offices, Shopping Malls,
 Community Development Sites, etc.
- Manage project budget & project resource allocation in coordination with concerned Architects, Engineers, Contractors engaged, verifying sub-contractors progress claims.

SENIOR ARCHITECT • ARCHIMEDES INDIA ASSOCIATES • 2016 – 2017

 Design documentation to site development including Healthcare Architecture, Interior Designing, and Project Management with respect to services in 750 bedded Teaching Hospital project.









IT SKILLS

Autodesk AutoCAD Microsoft Office Adobe Photoshop Sharepoint Sketchup 3ds Max Microsoft Project Revit

AFFILIATIONS

Council of Architecture – India CA/2016/74496

Senior Advisor for Safety Professionals Association of India SPAI/Confirmation/2019/615

Indian Institute of Architects – Gujarat Chapter

CERTIFICATIONS / TRAINING

Net Zero Energy Building – Process Driven Design – OAA, Ontario, Canada

ISO Auditor - ISO 9001:2008

Training in Business Etiquettes

Pursuing Fire Safety Officer certification by GIDM as a Specialist.

- Develop and establish Checks & Measures to ensure detailing in outputs for various services like HVAC, MEP, MGPS (Medical Gas Pipeline Systems, PTS (Pneumatic Tube Systems), etc.
- Ensure Design Validation process through personal visits to Sites, Interaction with end users, and feedback from clients and incorporating the same into design and development process.
- Manage project budget, execution status & project resource allocation in coordination with concerned Architects, Engineers, and Contractors engaged.

PROJECT ARCHITECT • RAM AGRI INFRA PVT. LTD. • 2010 – 2015

- Managing project cycle from post design to project closeout of a 450 acre land development and two Resort sites.
- Undertake preparation of Construction documentation, Tender documentation, approval of method statements and monitoring site work progress meeting its deadlines.
- Design and implementation of multistoried buildings, upmarket gated Villa communities, Mixed-use Township developments applying latest trends in lifestyle housing, materials and execution techniques/ green technologies.
- Interaction with vendors and concerned contractors verifying the subcontractors progress claims and carrying out final work measurements.
- Interaction with clients periodically, to ascertain their needs and develop design based reports, concepts and specifications for assigned projects.
- Coordination with Architect, Civil, Structural and MEP consultants for release of GFC drawings.

SENIOR ARCHITECT • HITECH OUTSOURCING SERVICES • 2006 – 2009

- As Man-month In-charge with Morrison Hershfield (US-Canada), generated revenue of more than 112k \$ consistently for the organization for six consecutive months in recession period.
- Ensured the highest levels of design quality, maintained client satisfaction, and exceeded expectations utilizing a team comprising of Architects, 3d Artists, Engineers & Draftsmen.
- Represented CAD Department as Head in maintaining the documentation for ISO 9001:2008 for three consecutive years.
- Initiated the use of Revit Architecture and ArchiCAD from training to implementation. Handled projects involved in Designing & Drafting, Detailing, CD Set making, and 3D Exterior & Interior Design.

JUNIOR ARCHITECT • RUDRA ASSOCIATES • 2003 – 2006

- Life-cycle of low-scale housing scheme projects from concept to execution.
- Spearhead coordination with agencies & sub-agencies.
- Detailed Working drawings in for project execution, updating and maintaining existing facility documentation.

EDUCATION

CERTIFICATION IN SMART CITIES PLANNING & DEVELOPMENT • 2017 • GUJARAT TECHNOLOGICAL UNIVERSITY GANDHINAGAR

BACHELOR OF ARCHITECTURE • 2003 • MS UNIVERSITY VADODARA







